CURRICULUM VITAE

NAME : IMWENE KENNEDY OMUKADA,

ADDRESS : **PO BOX 325-50408**,

Kamuriai- Kenya,

MOBILE NO : 0721-644971, 0729-459364 E-mail ADDRESS : <u>imwene2000@gmail.com</u>

PROFILE

I am a bachelor of science Analytical Chemistry graduate from the University of Nairobi with an ongoing Master's degree in Analytical Chemistry with specialized knowledge of principles of analytical Chemistry methods, and techniques. I am an accomplished Analytical chemist with a solid history of achievement in Agricultural, Animal products and environmental analysis. Areas of expertise include chromatographic methods, spectroscopic methods and classical techniques.

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

To gain knowledge and practical skills to become an efficient and all-round professional in a reputable and growing organization as well as be resourceful, competent and exemplary at work.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND:

Sep 2019-Date : UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI

MSc. Analytical Chemistry-(On-going).

2014 -2018 : UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI

BSc. Analytical Chemistry Second Upper Division

2002 - 2005 : S. A KOLANYA BOYS HIGH SCHOOL

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KSCE)

1994 - 2002 : KAMOLO PRIMARY SCHOOL

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (KCPE)

SOFT SKILLS:

Teamwork

- Member of the UNICSA-University of Nairobi (2015-2018).
- Both Graduate and Undergraduate Research student. (2018-Present)
- Participated in Church Choir competition at Ridgeways Catholic Church-2020

Organizational;

• Successfully combining study, part time work and extracurricular activities.

Communication;

• Report writing, seminar slides presentations for my university course and briefing/inducting the attaches, new interns and visitors.

Analytical thinking;

- Applying statistical and numerical techniques to process data.
- Data interpretation and forming structured arguments supported by evidence.

WORK AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

(1) November, 2019- Date: Central Veterinary Laboratory (CVL), Analytical Chemistry and Food Safety Laboratory- Kabete.

Post: (Public service commission internship program)-Analytical Chemist/Analyst.

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Toxicology and Aflatoxin Analysis.
- Pesticide Residue and Antibiotic Analysis.
- Heavy metal Analysis.
- Veterinary drugs analysis

(2) Jan. 2019-Nov. 2019 : Kenya Plant Health Inspectorate Service (KEPHIS)

Post: Analytical Chemist

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Analysis of pesticides MRLs on fresh produce.
- Analysis of water for irrigation suitability
- Analysis of organic and inorganic trace contaminants in plants, soil, crops, water and animal produce.
- Analysis of organic and inorganic ingredients in agro-inputs.
- Analysis of Aflatoxin in cereals, nuts and Tea matrices.

(3) Feb, 2011 – April 2011 : Mumias Sugar Company Limited

Post: Attachment

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Working in accordance of GLP, GMP and SOP requirements.
- Preparation of primary, Stock and Working standards.
- Analytical balances and Critical volumetric glassware verification.
- Sample Collection, Preservation, Preparation, Extraction.

OTHER PROFESSIONAL SKILLS ACQUIRED:

2020: Digital Program Ministry of ICT.

Data management/Entry and Virtual Assistant training by Ajira

2014: Driving License (DL No: 1907035-YVS 196)

Class B C E -Experience: Seven (7) years.

2010: Egerton University, Department of Engineering

Computer Packages Certificate

WORKSHOP AND TRAINING ATTENDED:

- 1. 10th Annual National Biosafety Conference (A Decade of Biosafety Regulatory Excellence), 2nd -5th November 2021 in Nairobi Kenya.
- 2. 3rd Phytosanitary Conference (Virtual Edition) 13th -16th September 2021-KEPHIS
- 3. Nuclear Magnetic Resonance training at the Kenya National-NMR Center, University of Nairobi, Kenya August, 2021.
- 4. African Material Research Society Conference on Nanotechnology Webinar August 2021
- 5. Workshop on Pan- African Covid-19 and Food Safety Webinar supported by University of Nairobi and the Institute for Food Safety at Cornell University, April 2021.
- 6. Training on HPTLC and ELISA screening at Directorate of veterinary services Labs-
- 7. Trained on Spectroscopic techniques (ICP-MS and ICP-OES), GFAAS, FAAS, CV-AAS at Kenya Plant Health Inspectorate Service-KEPHIS Headquarters-2019.
- 8. LC-MS/MS, GC-MS/MS, GC-MS, GC-Detectors and UHPLC training at Kenya Plant Health Inspectorate Service Headquarters-2019
- 9. Training on ISO 17025 at KEPHIS Headquarters Nairobi, March 2019
- 10. Data Analysis using Minitab 17/19, Microsoft Excel and JMP-(SAS).

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS AND PUBLICATIONS:

• Imwene K.O., Mbui D.N., Kinyua A.P., Mbugua J.K., Ahenda S and Onyatta J.O. (2021). Biotransformation of Biodegraded Organic Waste from a Batch Mode Microbial Fuel Cell to Organic Fertilizer. *Journal of Bioremediation and Biodegradation an open access journal ISSN: 2155-6199.* **12**(S8).

RESEARCH WORK COMPLETED:

- Analysis of Heavy Metals in Selected Foodstuffs from Different Estates in Nairobi Metropolitan Area. University of Nairobi, Chemistry Department-Pesticide Research Laboratory. (Undergraduate research work)
- Resource Recovery: Use of Microbial Fuel Cells in Electricity Production from Fruit Waste in Nairobi Kenya. (Master's Thesis due for Submission)

Research paper submitted for publication

• Current and Voltage data logging from Microbial Fuel Cells using ARDUINO BASED SENSORS.

Research Papers in Progress:

- Influence of optimized parameters on voltage and power production in Microbial Fuel Cells from fruit waste in Nairobi Kenya on going.
- Resource Recovery: Use of Microbial Fuel Cells in Electricity Production from Fruit Waste in Nairobi Kenya- on going.
- Emerging technologies for enhanced removal of residual antibiotics from source-separated urine and wastewaters: A Review- on going.
- Kinetic Modelling of Microbial Fuel Cells Voltage data from market fruit wastes in Nairobi City Kenya-on going.
- From Environment to Clinic: the role of pesticides and risk of antibiotic resistance evolution in selected market fruit wastes in Nairobi, Kenya- on going.

Research Interest:

Analytical Chemistry, Green Chemistry and Nanoscience

REFEREES:

Dr. Onyatta John Onam (Ph.D.)
Senior Lecturer,
P.O BOX 30197-00100, Nairobi, Kenya
Chemistry Department, University of Nairobi

Cell phone: +254722652159

E-mail: john.onyatta@uonbi.ac.ke

Dr. Damaris N. Mbui (Ph.D.)
Senior Lecturer,
P.O BOX 30197-00100, Nairobi, Kenya
Chemistry Department, University of Nairobi

Cell phone: +254723322033 E-mail: dmbui@uonbi.ac.ke

Dr. Vincent O. Madadi (Ph.D.)
Senior Lecturer,
P.O BOX 30197-00100, Nairobi, Kenya
Chemistry Department, University of Nairobi

Cell phone: +254720742415 E-mail: vmadadi@uonbi.ac.ke